Judith Crist Papers
Judith Crist Papers
1851-1971
Crist, Judith.
10 linear ft.
Papers of the American journalist; film, drama, and television critic; and author. Collection includes correspondence (1950-1970); manuscript and published articles; and book, film, television, and theatre reviews.
148917
Biographical History
Judith (Klein) Crist (1922- ) is an American film and drama critic. Born on 22 May 1922 in New York, she attended high school in New York City and graduated at the age of fifteen and received a B.A. from Hunter College in 1941. After teaching briefly at Washington State College, she completed work on an M.S. at the Columbia University School of Journalism in 1945. In the same year, she was hired by the New York Herald-Tribune as a general assignment reporter. Judith Klein married William B. Crist, a New York public relations executive, in 1947.
In 1958 Ms. Crist became associate drama critic under Walter Kerr, and in 1960 she was named editor for the arts for the Herald-Tribune. After the newspaper strike of 1962-1963, Judith Crist emerged as film critic and associate drama critic of the short lived New York World Journal Tribune. Beginning in 1965 she delivered short television film reviews on the NBC Today Show, as well as serving as a critic-at-large for the Ladies Home Journal from 1966 to 1967.
Ms. Crist conducted the Judith Crist Film Weekends at Tarrytown House, New York, from 1971 to 2006, and she has been an adjunct professor at Columbia's School of Journalism since 1958. She is a regular contributor of articles to various other national magazines and reviews network movies for TV Guide magazine and first-run films for New York magazine.
Judith Crist has received numerous awards, including the Page One Award of the New York Newspaper Guild (1955), the George Polk Award (1951), five N.Y. Newspaper Woman's Club awards (1955, 1959, 1963, 1965, 1967); Edn. Writers Association award (1952); and the Columbia Graduate School Journalism Alumni Award (1961). She is a member of the New York Film Critics and National Society of Film Critics associations and Sigma Tau Delta. A collection of her best pieces was published in an anthology entitled The Private Eye, The Cowboy and the Very Naked Girl (1968).
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Judith Crist Papers contain correspondence and writings, with a few items of memorabilia.
Correspondence consists of incoming letters and carbon copies of outgoing letters. There are numerous letters from readers of her reviews, as well as letters from actors, directors, and other persons notable in the performing arts. Notable correspondents include Bette Davis, Joan Crawford, Alfred Hitchcock, and Walt Disney.
Memorabilia contains newspaper clippings and a few miscellaneous items.
Writings in manuscript and printed form include articles, book reviews, interviews, and movie reviews. Titles of the first-run films reviewed in New York are given in the following inventory in the order they are treated in the review. Titles of the network movies reviewed in TV Guide are not listed.
Arrangement of the Collection
Correspondence is arranged chronologically. Writings are subdivided by type. Movie reviews for New York and TV Guide -- mostly revised typescripts and typescript carbons -- are arranged chronologically.
Related Material
has numerous collections relating to movies, television, and radio. Please refer to for a complete listing.
Subject and Genre Headings
Journalism; Popular culture; Radio, television, film; Women Authors; Crist, Judith -- Archives.; Criticism.; Critics -- United States.; Dramatic criticism.; Film criticism.; Film critics -- United States.; Journalism.; Newspapers -- Sections, columns, etc. -- Reviews.; Television criticism.; Theater critics -- United States.; Women authors, American.; Women film critics -- United States.; Women journalists -- United States.; Articles.; Correspondence.; Film reviews.; Manuscripts for publication.; Reviews (documents); Authors.; Critics.; Film critics.; Journalists.; Theater critics.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Judith K. Crist, 1969-1991.
Inventory
- Correspondence
  - 1951 (Box 1)
  - 1960 (Box 1)
  - 1962 (Box 1)
  - 1963, 13 folders (Box 1)
  - 1964, 13 folders (Box 1)
  - 1965 Jan-Jun, 7 folders (Box 1)
  - 1965 Jul-Dec, 6 folders (Box 2)
  - 1966 Jan-Apr, 4 folders (Box 2)
  - 1966 May-Dec, 8 folders (Box 3)
  - 1967, 12 folders (Box 3)
  - 1968 Jan-Jun, 6 folders (Box 3)
  - 1968 Jul-Dec, 6 folders (Box 4)
  - 1969 (Box 4)
  - 1970 (Box 4)
  - Undated (Box 4)
- Memorabilia
  - Newspaper clippings and magazine separates, 1960-1966 (Box 4)
  - Miscellaneous items, undated (Box 4)
- Writings
  - Album liners
    - Sound of Music, RCA, undated; typescript copy (Box 4)
    - "Upstairs at the Downstairs", 1965; typescript copy (Box 4)
  - Articles
    - On Entertainment in New York, 1965; typescript copy (Box 4)
    - On Films of the Thirties, 1965; typescript copy, galley proof (Box 4)
    - "Have We Gone Too Far With TV and Movies?", undated; typescript copy (Box 4)
    - "High School Movie Critic", undated; typescript copy (Box 4)
    - "The Love Goddess", undated; typescript (revised), typescript copy (Box 4)
    - "On Motion Pictures", Sep 1964 - Aug 1965; typescript copy (Box 4)
    - On Peter Sellers, ca.1965; typescript copy (Box 4)
    - On "Quickies" and Mini-Movies, undated; typescript copy (Box 4)
    - Untitled, undated (Box 4)
  - Book reviews
    - The Child Stars by Norman J. Zierold, 1965; typescript copy; published material (Box 4)
    - Harlow: An Intimate Biography by Irving Shulman; All My Sins Remembered by Elaine Barrymore; Elizabeth Taylor: Her Life, Her Loves, Her Future by Ruth Waterbury; The Rest of the Story by Sheilah Graham and All Told by Frederic O'Brady, undated; typescript copy (revised) (Box 4)
    - The Lonely Life: An Autobiography by Bette Davis, undated; published material (Box 4)
    - The Right Time by Harry Golden, undated; typescript copy (Box 4)
    - W.C. Fields: His Follies and Fortunes by Robert Lewis Taylor, 1967; published material (Box 4)
  - Fashion commentary
    - "Prominent Designers '66", 1966; typescript (revised) (Box 4)
  - Interviews
    - Catholic Home Messenger, 1966; published material (Box 4)
    - The Dartmouth, 1966; published material (Box 4)
    - The Promethean, 1966; published material (Box 4)
    - X-Press, 1966; published material (Box 4)
  - Movie reviews
    - New York Herald-Tribune
      - A Body in Every Bathtub, 1965; published material (Box 4)
      - Cleopatra, 1963; published material (Box 4)
      - The Taming of the Shrew, undated; published material (Box 4)
      - Ulysses, undated; published material (Box 4)
    - New York World Journal Tribune
      - Almost on Our Way to Maturity, 1967; published material (Box 4)
      - Balthazar, undated; published material (Box 4)
      - The Bible, 1966; published material; 2 folders (Box 4)
      - The Box-Office Numbers Game, 1967; published material (Box 4)
      - Crazy Quilt, 1966; published material (Box 4)
      - Cul-de-Sac and Fahrenheit 451, 1966; published material (Box 4)
      - Falstaff, 1967; published material (Box 4)
      - La Guerre Est Finie, undated; published material (Box 4)
      - The House of Mirth that Jerry Built, 1966; published material (Box 4)
      - In Like Flint, Hombre, Thoroughly Modern Millie, undated; published material (Box 4)
      - Is Paris Burning?, 1966; published material; 2 folders (Box 4)
      - Kaleidoscope, undated; published material (Box 4)
      - The Quiller Memorandum, The Night of the Generals, 1967; published material (Box 4)
      - Return of the Pre-Bond Man, 1966; published material (Box 4)
      - The Shameless Old Lady, 1966; published material (Box 4)
      - The Shameless Old Lady, Do You Keep a Lion at Home?, The Scene, Masculine Feminine, 1966; published material (Box 4)
    - New York Magazine
      - Very Happy Alexander, Don't Look Now, Hellfighters, Mayerling, Three in the Attic, Feb 24 1969 (Box 5)
      - The Prime of Miss Jean Brodie, Twisted Nerve, The Night of the Following Day, Adelaide, Mar 3 1969 (Box 5)
      - The Vixens, The Big Bounce, Skidoo, Mar 10 1969 (Box 5)
      - I am Curious (Yellow), 2, If.., The Castle, Where Eagles Dare, Otley, Mar 17 1969 (Box 5)
      - 2000 Years Later, Hieronymus Merkin, Baby Love, The Assassination Bureau, Mar 24 1969 (Box 5)
      - 100 Rifles, The Love Bug, Before Winter Comes, The Red and the White, Mar 31 1969 (Box 5)
      - Sweet Charity, Support Your Local Sheriff, Good-bye Columbus, Dracula Has Risen From the Grave, Apr 7 1969 (Box 5)
      - La Prisonniere, Pendulum, The Illustrated Man, The Wanderer, Apr 14 1969 (Box 5)
      - Doctor Glas, Hannibal Brooks, Run Angel Run, Apr 21 1960 (Box 5)
      - Teorema, The Guru, The Loves of Isadora, Salesman, King Murray, If It's Tuesday This Must Be Belgium, Apr 28 1969 (Box 5)
      - Mad Room, Lola Montes, Succubus, Miracle of Love, May 5 1969 (Box 5)
      - The Sweet Body of Deborah, Kenner, Hook, Line and Sinker, Lonesome Cowboys, Michael and Helga, The Roundup, May 12 1969 (Box 5)
      - The Valley of Gwangi, Laughter in the Dark, People Meet and Sweet Music Fills the Air, May 19 1969 (Box 5)
      - A Matter of Days, Where It's At, Midas Run, Death of a Gunfighter, The Libertine, Russ Meyer's Vixen, May 26 1969 (Box 5)
      - Midnight Cowboy, Popi, Winning, Southern Star, Hard Contract, Jun 2 1969 (Box 5)
      - The Green Slime, Those Daring Young Men in Their Jaunty Jalopies, Once Upon a Time in the West, Life, Love, Death, That Cold Day in the Park, Jun 9 1969 (Box 5)
      - Fraulein Doktor, You Only Love Once, The April Fools, Che!, Jun 16 1969 (Box 5)
      - Last Summer, The First Time, The Tree, The Fool Killer, McKenna's Gold, Ring of Bright Water, Eye of a Cat, Jun 23 1969 (Box 5)
      - Devil's Eight, The Lost Man, The Chairman, The Wild Bunch, My Side of the Mountain, Hello Down There, The Maltese Bippy, The Boys of Paul Street, Jun 30 1969 (Box 5)
      - True Grit, Slaves, 3 into 2 Won't Go, The Devil by the Tail, Jul 7 1969 (Box 5)
      - Marry Me! Marry Me!, The Wild Bunch, Krakatoa, East of Java, Jul 14 1969 (Box 5)
      - Easy Rider, Putney Swope, Me Natalie, How to Commit Marriage, Daddy's Gone A-Hunting, Death Rides a Horse, Jul 21 1969 (Box 5)
      - Run Wild, Run Free, Secret World, Whatever Happened to Aunt Alice?, Detour, Jul 28 1969 (Box 5)
      - Take the Money and Run, The Great Bank Robbery, Spirits of the Dead, The Learning Tree, Alice's Restaurant, Medium Cool, More, Who's That Knocking at My Door, Thank You All Very Much, A Place For Lovers, Staircase, The Rain People, Stiletto, Castle Keep, The Gypsy Moths, Bob and Carol and Ted and Alice, The Bridge at Remagen, The Italian Job, Sep 22 1969 (Box 5)
      - Butch Cassidy and the Sundance Kid, Number One, Two Gentlemen Sharing, Sep 29 1969 (Box 5)
      - Oh! What a Lovely War, The Adding Machine, All Neat in Black Stockings, The Christmas Tree, The File of the Golden Goose, Oct 6 1969 (Box 5)
      - Royal Hunt of the Sun, De Sade, Bob and Carol and Ted and Alice, Some Kind of Nut, Change of Mind, Oct 13 1969 (Box 5)
      - Madwoman of Chaillot, The Battle of Britain, The Bed Sitting Room, Lions Love, A Walk With Love and Death, Duet for Cannibals, All the Loving Couples, Oct 20 1969 (Box 5)
      - Adalen 31, The Sterile Cuckoo, Coming Apart, Lock Up Your Daughters, Oct 27 1969 (Box 5)
      - The Secret of Santa Vittoria, Rascal, Paint Your Wagon, Marlowe, Hail! Hero, American Revolution 2, Nov 3 1969 (Box 5)
      - Goodbye Mr. Chips, Downhill Racer, The Last of the Ski Bums, Sign of the Virgin, L'Immortelle, Nov 10 1969 (Box 5)
      - Trilogy, Futz, Journey to the Far Side of the Sun, Nov 17 1969 (Box 5)
      - The Arrangement, La Femme Infidele, Don't Drink the Water, The Brain, Flareu, Nov 24 1969 (Box 5)
      - Intimate Lighting, Kaya I'll Kill You!, Popcorn, Terry Whitmore, For Example, In the Year of the Pig, The Good Guys and the Bad Guys, Dec 1 1969 (Box 5)
      - Z, Alfred the Great, A Boy Named Charlie Brown, Dec 8 1969 (Box 5)
      - John and Mary, Cactus Flower, Dec 15 1969 (Box 5)
      - Hamlet, The Damned, The Reivers, Gaily, Gaily, Tell Them Willie Boy is Here, Generation, Three, Topaz, A Dream of Kings, Other Voices, Marooned, Dec 22 1969 (Box 5)
      - Hello Dolly!, On Her Majesty's Secret Service, They Shoot Horses Don't They?, The Happy Ending, Jan 12 1970 (Box 5)
      - What's Good for the Goose, The Last of the Mobile riot-Shots, Jan 19 1970 (Box 5)
      - M*A*S*H, Viva Max!, Anne of the Thousand Days, A Married Couple, The Activist, Without a Stitch, To Commit a Murder, Follow Me, Jan 26 1970 (Box 5)
      - The Milky Way, A Time in the Sun, The Looking Glass War, Other Voices, Prologue, Johnny Cash!, Feb 2 1970 (Box 5)
      - Patton, The Virgin Soldiers, The Honeymoon Killers, The Molly Maguires, The Kremlin Letters, House of Cards, Start the Revolution Without Me, Fando and Lis, Feb 9 1970 (Box 5)
      - End of the Road, Cat and Mouse, My Sweet Charlie, Tick..Tick..Tick, The Undefeated, Mumsy, Nanny, Sonny and Girly, Feb 16 1970 (Box 5)
      - Zabriskie Point, The Magic Christian, What Do You Say to a Naked Lady?, An Event, Feb 23 1970 (Box 5)
      - Ma Nuit Chez Maud, Me, Jenny, My Lover My Son, Grooving, Mar 2 1970 (Box 5)
      - Airport, The Only Game in Town, Tropic of Cancer, Loving, Bamse, Mar 9 1970 (Box 5)
      - Fellini Satyricon, Mar 16 1970 (Box 5)
      - King: A Filmed Record, The Boys in the Band, Love is a Funny Thing, The Ballad of Cable Hogue, The Lawyer, The Liberation of L.B. Jones, Dionysus in '69, Mar 23 1970 (Box 5)
      - Women In Love, Mar 30 1970 (Box 5)
      - The Sicilian Clan, Pussycat Pussycat I Love You, Apr 6 1970 (Box 6)
      - The Last Grenade, How to Succeed With Sex, Apr 13 1970 (Box 6)
      - Woodstock, Riverrun, Every Bastard a King, Brotherly Love, The Adventurers, Apr 20 1970 (Box 6)
      - Mississippi Mermaid, Cherry, Harry and Raquel, Bloody Mama, Halls of Anger, Apr 27 1970 (Box 6)
      - Diary of a Schizophrenic Girl, Hi Mom!, A Man Called Horse, The Forbin Project, The Walking Stick, May 4 1970 (Box 6)
      - Serafino, Leo the Last, Zig-Zag, May 11 1970 (Box 6)
      - Getting Straight, In Search of Gregory, Sympathy for the Devil (1+1), May 18 1970 (Box 6)
      - Naked Hearts, The Passenger, I am Curious (Blue), Brand X, Too Late the Hero, Dunwich Horror, Scream and Scream Again, Paddy, May 25 1970 (Box 6)
      - Rider on the Rain, The Grasshopper, The Landlord, Watermelon Man, The Dreamer, Jun 1 1970 (Box 6)
      - Let It Be, Beneath the Planet of the Apes, The Out-Of-Towners, Stanley Sweetheart, The Way We Live Now, Jun 8 1970 (Box 6)
      - The Passion of Anna, Jovita, One More Time, Jun 15 1970 (Box 6)
      - The Virgin and the Gypsy, A Walk in the Spring Rain, Kelly's Heroes, Jun 22 1970 (Box 6)
      - Catch-22, Strawberry Statement, Cotton Comes to Harlem, The Hawaiians, On a Clear Day You Can See Forever, Censorship in Denmark, Events, El Condor, Jun 29 1970 (Box 6)
      - Tell Me that You Love Me, Junie Moon, Two Mules for Sister Sara, The Boatniks, Freedom to Love, The Gifts, Jul 16 1970 (Box 6)
      - Myra Breckinridge, Beyond the Valley of the Dolls, The Revolutionary, Jul 13 1970 (Box 6)
      - Joe, Quackser Fortune Has a Cousin in the Bronx, The Cowards, Jul 20 1970 (Box 6)
      - Something for Everyone, Entertaining Mr. Sloane, Darling Lili, Hello-Goodbye, They Call Me Mr. Tibbs!, Jul 27 1970 (Box 6)
      - The Christine Jorgensen Story, Chisum, Move, The Angel Levine, Out of It, Dreams of Glass, Darker than Amber, Pound, The McMasters, Soldier Blue, The Rise of Louis XIV, The Wild Child, Tristana, Five Easy Pieces, Kes, The Diary of a Mad Housewife, The People Next Door, Lovers and Other Strangers, The Things of Life, Borsalino, The Bird With the Crystal Plumage, A Quiet Place in the Country, R.P.M., Sep 28 1970 (Box 6)
      - Tora! Tora! Tora!, Sunflower, The Baby Maker, Goodbye Gemini, Quiet Days in Clichy, Oct 5 1970 (Box 6)
      - Pieces of Dreams, First Love, The Great White Hope, Oct 12 1970 (Box 6)
      - Goin Down the Road, The Act of the Heart, Trash, Monte Walsh, Give Her the Moon, The Mind of Mr. Soames, Oct 19 1970 (Box 6)
      - I Never Sang for My Father, This Man Must Die, Little Fauss and Big Halsey, Ice, Time of Roses, Oct 26 1970 (Box 6)
      - Perfect Friday, The Pizza Triangle, The McKenzie Break, Dirty Dingus Magee, Groupies, Nov 16 1970 (Box 6)
      - The Confession, Adam at 6 AM, Homer, Elvis: That's the Way It Is, There's a Girl in my Soup, The Travelling Executive, Dec 14 1970 (Box 6)
      - Little Big Man, Investigation of a Citizen Above Suspicion, The Man With Connections, Husbands, Take a Girl Like You, Dec 21 1970 (Box 6)
      - The Projectionist, The Music Lovers, The Last Valley, Zachariah, Feb 1 1971 (Box 6)
      - Say Hello to Yesterday, Doctor's Wives, Puzzle of a Downfall Child, Julius Caesar, Ramparts of Clay, Little Murders, Feb 8 1971 (Box 6)
      - The Vampire Lovers, Cult of the Damned, The Statue, Sudden Terror, Rio Lobo, The Wild Country, The Night Visitor, The Garden of Delights, Feb 15 1971 (Box 6)
      - Wuthering Heights, Claire's Knee, Pigeons, The Body, Feb 22 1971 (Box 6)
      - The Pursuit of Happiness, The Tender Moment, Wanda, Get Carter, Mar 1 1971 (Box 6)
      - The Phantom Tollbooth, The Priest's Wife, The Sporting Club, Mar 8 1971 (Box 6)
      - Cold Turkey, Dead of Summer, Double Suicide, Beyond Love and Evil, Mar 15 1971 (Box 6)
      - The Andromeda Strain, The Conformist, The Transient Life, Making It, The Buttercup Chain, Mar 22 1971 (Box 6)
      - A New Leaf, A Severed Head, When Dinosaurs ruled the Earth, Mad Dogs and Englishmen, THX 1138, Vanishing Point, Brother John, Mar 29 1971 (Box 6)
      - Friends, Melody, Shut Up..I'm Crying, Taking Off, Gass!, Flight of the Doves, Apr 5 1971 (Box 6)
      - Shinbone Alley, Celebration at Big Sur, P.S. I Love You, And Soon the Darkness, The Beguiled, Apr 12 1971 (Box 6)
      - Margo, The Mephisto Waltz, The Blood on Satan's Claw, The Beast in the Cellar, Valdez is Coming, Waterloo, Apr 19 1971 (Box 6)
      - Derby, The House That Dripped Blood, La Collectioneuse (The Collectress), Pretty Maids All in a Row, Summer of '42, Apr 26 1971 (Box 6)
      - Bananas, Sweet Sweetback's Badass Song, My Secret Life, Saturday Morning, Skezag, May 3 1971 (Box 6)
      - Percy, Guess What!?!, May 10 1971 (Box 6)
      - The Crook, 10 Rillington Place, Mrs. Pollifax: Spy, Red Sky at Morning, May 17 1971 (Box 6)
      - Plaza Suite, A Day in the Life of Ivan Denisovich, Blue Water, White Death, May 24 1971 (Box 6)
      - The Cop (Un Conde), They Might Be Giants, Support Your Local Gunfighter, The Night Digger, The Barefoot Executive, May 31 1971 (Box 6)
      - The Cat O'Nine Tails, When Eight Bells Toll, Escape from the Planet of the Apes, Daughters of Darkness, Dirtymouth, Jun 7 1971 (Box 6)
      - The Clowns, Walkabout, Drive, He Said, The Grissom Gang, Big Jake, Villain, A Man Called Sledge, Jun 14 1971 (Box 7)
      - Unman, Wittering and Zigo, Summertree, That Splendid November, The Anderson Tapes, The Deserter, Jun 21 1971 (Box 7)
      - Death in Venice, Harry Kellerman, Klute, Fortune and Men's Eyes, Willard, Jun 28 1971 (Box 7)
      - Peter Rabbit and the Tales of Beatrix Potter, Willie Wonka and the Chocolate Factory, Shaft, Panic in Needle Park, The Hellstrom Chronicle, The Language of Love, Wild Rovers, Le Mans, Murphy's War, The Nun, McCabe and Mrs. Miller, Carnal Knowledge, Glory Boy, Jul 15 1971 (Box 7)
      - Adrift, Two-Lane Blacktop, Evel Knievel, What's the Matter with Helen?, Jul 12 1971 (Box 7)
      - Dusty and Sweets McGee, The Panic in Needle Park, The Seven Minutes, The Last Run, Jul 19 1971 (Box 7)
      - The Go-Between, Figures in a Landscape, The Touch, The Devils, Jul 26 1971 (Box 7)
      - Sunday Bloody Sunday, Desperate Characters, Been Down So Long It Looks Like Up to Me, You've Got to Walk It Like You Talk It, Funnyman, The Trojan Women, Maidstone, The Steagle, Sep 27 1971 (Box 7)
      - The Last Picture Show, The Debut, Kotch, Skin Game, Millhouse, Oct 4 1971 (Box 7)
      - The Last Movie, Sacco and Vanzetti, Long Ago Tomorrow, Zeppelin, Directed by John Ford, What Fixed Me, Decameron, Dodes' ka-den, Oct 11 1971 (Box 7)
      - Le Souffle au Coeur (Murmur of the Heart), Punishment Park, It Only Happens to Others, Bunny O'Hare, Oct 18 1971 (Box 7)
      - The French Connection, The Organization, The Gladiators, The Todd Killings, T. R. Baskin, Catlow, Oct 25 1971 (Box 7)
      - Joe Hill, Bless the Beasts and Children, WR--Mysteries of the Organism, Medea, A Safe Place, Nov 1 1971 (Box 7)
      - The Railway Children, Three Lives, Some of My Best Friends Are..., Is There Sex. After Death?, Nov 8 1971 (Box 7)
      - Fiddler on the Roof, Jennifer on My Mind, Born to Win, El Topo, Nov 15 1971 (Box 7)
      - Bedknobs and Broomsticks, Who Killed Mary Whatsername, 200 Motels, One Night at Dinner, Maddalena, Nov 22 1971 (Box 7)
      - Black Beauty, Who Says I Can't Ride a Rainbow!, Man in the Wilderness, Raga, Nov 29 1971 (Box 7)
    - Television Scripts
      - "Adventure Movies", 1965; typescript (Box 7)
      - "Agony", undated; typescript copy (revised), typescript (Box 7)
      - "Bond", 1965; typescript (Box 7)
      - "Choice", 1965; typescript (Box 7)
      - "Horror Films", 1965; typescript (Box 7)
      - "Oscars", 1965; typescript (Box 7)
      - "Shock", undated; typescript copy (revised) (Box 7)
      - "Summer Laughter", 1965; typescript (Box 7)
    - TV Guide Magazine
      - Network Movies
        - 1969 Feb 8 - Dec 27, annotated typescript drafts; 48 folders (Box 7)
        - 1970 Jan 3 - Dec 26, annotated typescript drafts; 53 folders (Box 8)
        - 1971 Jan 2 - Aug 14, annotated typescript drafts; 33 folders (Box 8)
    - Miscellaneous
      - Notes, lists and fragments, 1969; undated; holograph, typescript (Box 8)
      - The Birthday Party, undated; typescript copy, typescript copy (revised) (Box 8)
      - Far From the Madding Crowd, undated; typescript copy (Box 8)
      - Love Affair and Father, 1967; typescript copy, typescript copy (revised) (Box 8)
      - Smashing Time, undated; typescript copy (Box 8)
      - Windy Day, undated; holograph (Box 8)
      - Theatre reviews (Box 8)
      - The Apple Tree, undated; published material (Box 8)
      - Mrs. Daily, 1965; typescript copy (Box 8)
      - A Rainless Sky, undated; typescript reproduction (Box 8)